Your Highness.
世子
Are you all right?
您没事吧
Yes.
没事
I was just a bit dizzy.
我就刚才恍惚了一下
What do you think this picture indicates?
你觉着这幅画什么意思
This picture
这画
has nothing to do
和这文字
with the text content.
并没有什么关系啊
When you look at this picture,
你看这幅画的时候
do you have any special feelings?
有没有什么特别的感觉
It's just a normal picture.
就是一幅普通的画
Never mind.
没什么
Let's continue.
先往下看吧
It's you again!
又是你
Is it you
那木盒子
who gave him the wooden box?
你给他的
If I reply,
我若回答你
will you let me climb up?
你让我上去吗
You want to climb up
上来
and kill him?
杀他
Or why would I take the trouble?
不然我费这么大力做什么
No way.
不行
Too many people in Yangcheng would notice me
阳城人多眼杂
so I didn't want to fight you there.
我不和你出手
But things are different here.
但在这可不一样
I advise you one last time.
我最后劝你一遍
We can join hands
我们可以合作
to kill Xu Fengnian.
杀徐凤年
But I don't want that.
不好
Miss,
姑娘
you should
做人
at least be reasonable!
要讲道理啊
In this biography,
从内容上看
many testimonies from witnesses have been collected.
这里收集了不少证人证词
That night,
那一晚
Wang Xianzhi was indeed in the capital.
王仙芝确实在京城
Not all testimonies
证词
are true.
未必是真的
Witnesses mentioned in it
这里边提到的人
are mostly alive.
大多还活着
It's not hard to confirm.
想询问一下真假并不难
I think
我觉得
the testimonies are true.
他说的是真的
Even if Wang Xianzhi was in the capital that night,
就算王仙芝当时在京城
he might not be the assassin.
也未必是他出手
Honestly,
说实话
Her Grace
王妃当时
had excellent swordsmanship.
虽然剑法神通
But if Wang Xianzhi fought her,
可王仙芝真要出手
she wouldn't have left the capital alive.
她不可能活出京城
It at least proves that Wang Xianzhi was involved.
但至少说明王仙芝跟此事有关
I guess this is why
这个木盒的突然出现
the wooden box was suddenly given to you.
应该就是要你这么想
I understand.
我明白
I'm going to Wudi City.
我这一行就是要去武帝城
When I see this and get disturbed,
到时候我看了这个心绪大乱
I'll fight Wang Xianzhi directly.
到时候直接对王仙芝出手了
Then, the trick to get me killed by Wang Xianzhi
这借刀杀人的把戏
will be achieved.
就得逞了
Your Highness.
世子
I'm glad you understand that.
世子明白就好
But this is a clue, anyway.
可这毕竟是找到一点线索
Over the years,
这么多年了
the truth is finally beginning to come out.
真相终于浮出一点来了
I protected Huangman'er
我保护黄蛮儿
and my sisters
保护大姐二姐
because I promised my mother
就是因为我答应我娘
that I would defend our family for her.
我要替她守住这个家
My mother is still in my heart.
我心里边我娘一直还在
She's watching me.
她一直看着我呢
I won't let her down.
不能让我娘失望
I'll find out who murdered her.
我一定要找出害她那个凶手
Your Highness.
世子
I'm all right.
我没事
I'm just...
我就是
I'm just a bit disturbed
我就是好不容易找到线索
when I've found a clue after all the trouble.
心里有点乱
Don't worry, Grandpa Wei.
魏爷爷放心
I won't do silly things
我不会做傻事
or act on impulse.
也不会冲动
Leave me alone for a while.
你就让我一个人坐会儿
I'll think about the whole story.
我好好想想前因后果
If you need anything,
有什么需要
let me know.
你随时叫我
I will.
好
Why is the dragon gone?
这龙怎么没了
Senior Li?
李前辈
Grandpa Wei?
魏爷爷
Mother?
娘
Fengnian.
凤年
Those who cross Heaven's Gate
过天门者
can override all mortals.
则可凌驾众生
But I'm not convinced.
可我偏偏不服
I'm not convinced that destiny controls life,
不服天道能定人生
that we can't fight against fate,
不服命运无法抗争
that man can't conquer nature,
不服人无法胜天
or that the Unity can be immortal.
不服天人便是仙神
I can use my sword
我有我手中剑
to break open the Heaven's Gate.
斩开天门
Even if demons and immortals come to the mortal world,
就算古今神魔皆临凡尘
I'll kill them with my sword!
我李淳罡皆以一剑斩之
I can cut off the destiny
斩去天命
and remove the shackles.
斩去枷锁
With the unyielding spirit,
我有这不屈在手
I can cut off all the hesitation
便可斩去一切彷徨无措
and fear in my heart.
斩去心中畏惧阴霾
Go away, destiny!
去你的天道
I have a blade,
我有一刀
to kill the dragon!
可斩天龙
to kill the Unity!
可斩天人
Mother.
娘
So, it's a dream?
是梦啊
You didn't expect to see me, did you?
没想到吧
Hey.
喂
Time to yell for help.
还不叫人救你
You're wounded?
你受伤了
I fought with someone by the cliff.
在悬崖上跟人打了一架
Not a big problem.
问题不大
Were there a lot of people
悬崖上
by the cliff?
人很多
A lot of them.
多
They all came to kill you.
都是来杀你的
You're sought after.
你挺抢手啊
Where's the man who hurt you?
打伤你的人呢
Off the cliff.
下去了
Running into an insane girl is the biggest trouble.
最麻烦就是遇上疯子
Hope Mr. Zhao Huangchao's plan will work.
希望赵黄巢前辈说的都是真的
The day is breaking.
天都亮了
The fight last night was in vain.
白打一晚上
Go.
走
Let's go for breakfast.
吃早饭去
Don't you yell for help yet?
你还不叫人救你
I'm really going to kill you.
我真杀你了
The sun is coming out.
太阳要出来了
In a little while,
再过一会儿
the sunrise will be spectacular.
会很好看
Shall we enjoy the scenery
要不我们一起赏个景
before the fight?
再搏命吧
Why not?
行啊
It's indeed spectacular.
是很好看
Why are you crying?
你怎么哭了
I dreamed of my mother.
我梦见我娘了
She...
她
She's gorgeous, isn't she?
很好看吧
You're handsome.
你这么好看
Your mother must be beautiful.
你娘一定也好看
Over the years,
这么多年
I don't want to believe
其实我一直不相信
that she's dead.
她已经走了
I always think
我一直觉得
that she's living in my heart.
她活在我心里
Actually, I'm deceiving myself.
其实是我在骗我自己
What makes you say that?
为什么这么说
She bade farewell to me in my dream.
她在梦里跟我告别了
She died.
她走了
A long time ago.
早就走了
I just didn't accept the truth
只是我到现在
until now.
才承认这一点
Did you bid farewell to her
你在梦里
in your dream?
跟她告别了吗
It was too late.
没来得及
The scenery is beautiful today.
今天的景色是很美
For its sake,
看在美景的分上
I'm not going to kill you.
不杀你了
Why do you insist on killing me?
你为什么一定要杀我
I don't believe you do that for the gold only.
我不相信你就为了千两黄金
See you.
再见
It's not too late.
来得及的
Excuse me?
你说什么
Farewell.
说再见啊
As long as you bid farewell to her,
只要你说出口
she will hear you.
想听的人就一定会听见
Mother,
娘
farewell.
走好
(Biography of Wu Su) This is the dragon
你在梦里见到的天龙
you saw in your dream.
就是这样的
Did some patterns
仅凭几套纹路
and a picture
一幅图形
get me into a dream?
就能让人入梦
They only worked on you.
只对你有用
The one who prepared this
准备这些的人
must have known you very well.
应该对你了解颇深
Did he do this
这功法
only to make His Highness have a nightmare?
就只是为了让世子做个噩梦吗
He wanted to use the nightmare
这是借梦境毁去
to ruin the dependence and reliance
一个人心中
in your heart.
最重要的屏障和依靠
I guess in your heart, your mother is the most important.
你娘应该是你心中最重要的那个人
Right.
是
He wanted to attack you spiritually
这是想从心灵上给你打击
so that you would break down and become desperate.
让你崩溃绝望
How did you get over it?
你怎么扛过来的
I destroyed them in my dream.
我把他们斩了
If you hadn't taught me
要不是前辈
Open the Heaven's Gate,
告诉我一剑开天门
I wouldn't have managed to do that.
我恐怕斩不出这一刀
Not everybody can make it.
不是每个人都能斩出这一刀的
Now that you've got over it,
抗过这一关
no tricks of this kind
以后这类型的功法
can influence you anymore.
将无法再影响你了
But who do you think
可是
sent this to us?
到底是谁送过来的呢
No matter who sent it,
不管是谁送的
he'll come again.
他还会再来
Let's set out.
起程
To Mount Longhu!
去龙虎山
His Majesty summoned you to the palace.
陛下召你进宫
Let me sleep for a bit longer.
我再睡会儿
Why did His Majesty
他这时候
summon me at this time of day?
这时候召我进什么宫
An urgent message came from Yangzhou
泱州急报
that your son met Cao Changqing in Yangcheng.
你儿子在阳城遇到曹长卿了
One of the top three martial artists?
天下前三
Your son's maid is the princess of West Chu.
你儿子的侍女是西楚公主
You know that, don't you?
这事你知道吧
I do.
知道
Then why do you keep her in your mansion?
知道你还把西楚公主养在府里
When the princess
让公主
serves as a maid,
当侍女
it's the pride of North Liang.
这才显得咱北椋霸气
Cao Changqing
曹长卿
recognized the princess
认出了西楚公主
and fought your son!
对你儿子出手了
Li Chungang was around him, wasn't he?
那不是还有这个李淳罡呢
Li Chungang and Cao Changqing
李淳罡
had a fight, but neither of them won.
交手一招未分胜负
Before Cao Changqing left, he said
临走的时候传下话
that he would go back to West Shu.
要重回蜀地
Your son's maid
你家那侍女
would be the queen.
将是女王
When the queen serves as his maid,
让女王当侍女
he'll be imposing.
这回他威风大了
Imposing?
还威风呢
Evidence shows
从各方面查证来看
that Jiang Ni
那个叫姜泥的
has been trying to kill Xu Fengnian since she was little.
从小就尝试要刺杀徐凤年
Looks like
看来
she hates him a lot.
仇深似海啊
My son
我儿子啊
will be stuck in romance tricks.
命里有桃花劫
Girls all hate him.
女人都恨他
Do you get it?
你想明白了没有
The new queen of West Chu wants to kill Xu Fengnian.
新一代楚国女王要杀徐凤年
At last, I can
这回我终于可以
have a sound sleep.
睡一个踏实觉喽
Seriously?
你还真睡啊
Xu Xiao!
徐骁
Ouch.
哎哟
Don't yell.
别嚷嚷
Come on.
来来来
Lie down with me.
一块儿跟我这躺会儿
The wind is rising.
起风了
Any problem?
有问题
Jiang Ni?
姜泥
Keep your voice down.
小声些
Cao Changqing made the wind rise?
是曹长卿引起风沙
I asked him to cover me
是我让棋诏叔叔掩人耳目
so that I could sneak back.
我才能偷偷溜回来
I thought Cao Changqing would stop you from coming back.
我还以为曹长卿不会让你回来
When you're in danger,
如果你遇到危险
Cao Changqing won't help to save you
有姜泥在你身边
unless Jiang Ni is around you.
曹长卿才能可能出手救人
Do you get it?
懂吗
I came back to ask you for money.
我是回来要钱的
I've served as your maid for so many years.
当你侍女这么多年
When I have to leave,
我要走了
shouldn't you give me some allowance?
你总得给点安家费吧
When you're really leaving,
等你真走了
I'll give it to you.
就给你
I've promised Mr. Chess Master
我跟棋诏叔叔说好了
that after you leave Mount Longhu safely,
等你平安离开龙虎山
I'm going to West Shu.
我就真要去西蜀了
Anyway,
不过
he also said
棋诏叔叔也说了
that our residence in West Shu
我们在西蜀
would be a good thing for North Liang.
对北椋是好事
I would rather that you stayed.
我宁愿你留下来
So that you could order me about?
留下来被你使唤吗
All right.
好啦
You should be careful.
你留意着点
Except those who you trust,
除了身边最信任的人
don't let anyone know
你可别让别人知道
that I'm back.
我又回来了
What about Yu Youwei?
鱼幼薇呢
She's staying with Mr. Chess Master.
她在棋诏叔叔身边
He said
棋诏叔叔说
he would tell her
要把西楚各路义士
about all supporters of West Chu.
都给她交代清楚
She'll be my lady-in-waiting.
以后她就是我的直属女官了
Her Grace isn't noticed, is she?
殿下没被发现吧
What if I kill Xu Fengnian?
如果杀了徐凤年会怎么样
Without a reason,
好好的
why must you kill Xu Fengnian?
为什么要杀徐凤年
When Her Grace has her way to go,
公主要走自己的路
she can't be stuck in love affairs.
就不能有情感羁绊
Only a loner
孤家寡人
can establish the monarchy.
才能成帝王之业
Nonsense.
胡扯
I made a slip of the tongue.
我说错话了
I didn't mean that.
我不是这个意思
I get it.
我知道了
I won't kill Xu Fengnian, then.
那就不杀徐凤年
When Li Chungang is around,
有李淳罡在
I can't kill Xu Fengnian, anyway.
杀不了
Xu Xiao?
徐骁
When His Majesty has summoned you,
此时陛下让你进宫
there'll be a result
你儿子世袭罔替的事
for your son's inheritance problem.
它就有结果了
But you're ignoring His Majesty.
你弄出一个无视君恩的样子
What...?
这
What do you want?
做什么呀
I don't want to do anything.
我什么也不想做
He's kept me here for so many days without seeing me.
他让我在这闲置了这么多天
Why can't I keep him waiting, too?
我还不能让他等会儿
It's not time to be angry with His Majesty.
现在不是赌气的时候
Why don't you understand?
你怎么就看不明白呢
The more arrogant I pretend to be,
现在我表现的越狂悖
the more relieved His Majesty will feel.
那陛下就越放心
All right. All right.
好好好
You always make sense.
全都是你的理
If you still don't go,
你要是再不去啊
the carriages from the palace
宫里的马车
will block the gate.
全堵你门口了
Why are you lying down again?
怎么又躺下了
You're right.
对对对
I shouldn't push it.
也不能太过了
Let's go to the palace.
那咱们就去宫里走一趟
Oh, yes.
哎呀
That's great.
好好好
Be patient.
着什么急
You were tricked
你被人设计
and caught in a nightmare?
陷入噩梦
Who did that?
谁干的
This is what confuses me.
问题就出在这儿
I can't figure out who's capable enough to trick me.
我想不出来谁有这手段
Why are you staring at me?
你看我干什么
He's an idiot.
他是笨蛋
And he isn't experienced in the martial world.
又不算真的闯过江湖
It makes sense that he can't recognize martial tricks.
对功法手段不了解也正常
But what about you?
那你呢
You're the God of Sword.
你可是剑神
You have no idea, too?
你也没头绪
I...
我
I've been hiding under Tingchao Pavilion
我在听潮亭底下
for so many years.
躲了这么多年
How do I know
这些年来
what masters have appeared
江湖上多了哪些高手
in the martial world in recent years?
我哪知道啊
I'll go ask Mr. Chess Master later.
那我晚点去问棋诏叔叔
What about the female assassin?
那女刺客呢
Why didn't she kill you at that time?
当时为什么不动手
I don't think
我总觉得
she wanted to kill me.
她的目的未必是杀我
Let's think about it.
现在回头想想
Did she hurt me twice
那两次重伤
just to kill me?
真的是害我吗
After she assassinated me for the first time,
那次之后
I rose from the dead.
我破而后立
I absorbed the genuine spirit forcibly
把真气强行吸收
and enhanced Dahuangting to the fourth level.
将大黄庭推至四重
And then,
再之后
she assassinated me in Yangcheng.
就是阳城
As the saying goes,
要说呢
fortune and misfortune are intertwined.
祸福相依
Your wound
这伤啊
would be helpful, anyway.
也算来得及时
When I killed Liu Liting in Yangcheng,
在阳城我杀刘黎廷
I could have caused problems.
本该会有后患
But her assassination
但偏偏这次刺杀
caught the Lu Family in a dilemma.
让卢家进退两难
Just because I was wounded,
反而借伤势
the crisis was defused.
将危机化解于无形
Two assassinations
这两次刺杀
were helpful to me.
带给我的都是好处
So, you think she's been helping you?
所以你认为她是在帮你
Before today's sunrise,
今天日出之前
she had the best chance to kill me.
是她杀我最佳时机
But she didn't.
但她却没有动手
Could it be
难不成
another arrangement of Xu Xiao's?
又是徐骁的布局啊
I don't know.
不知道
As I'm going east,
经过这次东行
I feel
我觉得自己
that I just can't see through Xu Xiao.
越来越看不透徐骁了
You came early, Prime Minister Zhang.
这张宰辅来得早啊
Who else is coming?
还有人来吗
His Majesty also summoned General Gu Jiantang.
陛下还召了大将军顾剑棠入宫
Unfortunately,
无奈
he's having a recurrence of the wound.
顾将军旧伤复发
Today,
今日
he can't come.
来不了了
Of course, a coward like him
这胆小如鼠之人
doesn't dare to come and see me.
自然不敢来见我
During the national wars,
春秋国战
there were four famous generals.
四大名将
Gu Jiantang is as famous as you.
顾剑棠与上柱国齐名
After Liyang ruled the world,
离阳一统后
you settled
上柱国
in North Liang
盘踞北椋
and became the lord.
画地为王
Gu Jiantang, however,
而顾剑棠
abandoned his troops
抛下部曲
and came to the capital alone.
孤身入京
For national affairs,
为天下事
he has been straining every nerve.
尽心竭力
Our people
孰忠孰奸
will judge
天下人
who is loyal and who is treacherous.
自有公论
Without doubt,
自然是
a sinister man
顾剑棠
like Gu Jiantang
这阴损之货
is the most loyal.
才是最忠
So,
所以
maybe he can be
顾剑棠或许
the best candidate
才是接手北椋的
to take over North Liang.
最好人选
If he takes over North Liang,
他接手北椋
will His Majesty
那陛下
feel relieved?
能放心吗
Don't gossip about His Majesty.
请勿妄议君王
I'll say no more.
不说了
Where's His Majesty?
陛下人呢
He summoned me.
是他找我来的
Why hasn't he appeared yet?
怎么不露面
His Majesty is feeling unwell
陛下身体不适
and he won't see you.
就不见上柱国了
Then why did he summon me?
那召我进宫做甚
Here's an oral instruction.
陛下口谕
His Majesty wants to ask you a question.
要问上柱国
If your son takes over North Liang
北椋保住世袭罔替
and inherits the throne of North Liang,
世子继承了北椋王位
do you still want to be Grand Commander?
还想不想上柱国一职
When doing business,
买卖吗
people gain some and lose some.
有得有失
I understand.
我懂
What do you understand?
你懂什么
I'm too old and muddleheaded
臣年迈昏昧
to take such an important post.
不堪重任
Tomorrow, I'll submit a report
明日就上书
to resign as Grand Commander.
请辞上柱国之位
Good.
好
According to His Majesty,
陛下说了
you don't need to kneel for this.
就不要接旨那一套繁琐的事了
Now that you resign as Grand Commander,
王爷既然请辞上柱国
the throne of North Liang
那北椋王位
should be inherited by your son.
自然该世袭罔替
The North Liang Army
下一任北椋旗
will still belong to the Xu Family.
还是姓徐
This is a national affair.
这是朝堂
Do you really take it as a business deal?
真当是商贾交易吗
Don't be angry, Prime Minister.
宰辅息怒
His Majesty said
陛下说了
that North Mang cast covetous eyes on us
北莽虎视眈眈
and the people of West Chu wanted to make trouble.
楚人又蠢蠢欲动
We're threatened by growing crises.
可谓是危机四伏啊
We need
还需
North Liang Army to defend the world
北椋镇守天下
and relieve worries from His Majesty.
为国解忧呢
The hereditary system of North Liang
北椋世袭罔替
will cause trouble in the future.
未来终是祸端
I...
臣
I ask to see His Majesty.
请见陛下
His Majesty is feeling unwell
陛下不适
and he won't see you.
就不见了
One more thing.
还有啊
His Majesty ordered
陛下说了
that Prime Minister Zhang
今日之事
should be the witness of this case.
特地请张宰辅做个见证
In the future,
日后朝堂之上
no officials shall make improper comments.
希望不要有人对此事妄加评论
How can we stop others
悠悠众口
from commenting?
堵得住吗
No one else can stop them.
旁人堵不住
But you can, of course.
张宰辅自然无妨
Looks like in His Majesty's eyes,
看来在陛下心里啊
Prime Minister Zhang,
张宰辅
you can awe all the other officials.
一人就可以震慑百官
His Majesty thinks so highly of you.
如此重信
I'm indeed jealous.
让人羡慕
I...
臣
I've been racking my brains
殚精竭虑
for the prosperity of Liyang.
一心只为离阳盛世
God knows how loyal I am.
此心天地可昭
Don't worry, Prime Minister.
宰辅放心
I'll tell His Majesty
你这话
what you just said.
我定会禀于陛下
Han Shengxuan,
韩生宣
North Liang still belongs to my family.
今后北椋还是姓徐
What do you think of it?
你怎么想啊
Thank you, My Lord,
难为王爷
for remembering my name.
还记得我这贱名
The ownership of North Liang
至于北椋姓什么
is a national affair.
那是朝堂政事
I don't dare to comment.
我怎敢多嘴啊
People call you Han Diaosi.
人人都叫你韩貂寺
After this name is used for a long time,
这叫多了
don't forget
韩生宣是你的本名
your real name Han Shengxuan.
可别忘了
I'm from a humble family.
小人起于微末
I don't dare to forget my real name.
自不敢忘
A man
人吗
should not
一呢
forget his origin.
不能忘本
Also,
二
he should not overstep his authority.
就是不能僭越
I'll keep in mind
王爷教诲
your instruction, My Lord.
谨记于心
Hereditament. Hereditament.
世袭罔替 世袭罔替
A lot of people tried to stop it,
阻拦的人还真不少
but I made it at last.
最后成了
Shouldn't you congratulate me?
可喜可贺
All right.
好了
I'm going back to North Liang.
回我的北椋了
His Majesty
陛下
indeed approved of the hereditament
果然把世袭罔替
for North Liang.
给了徐骁
(Zhao Danping, Longhu Arch-Taoist) What will Xu Xiao exchange
那徐骁
for that?
拿什么换
He resigned as Grand Commander.
请辞上柱国
Grand Commander is a glorious position,
上柱国一职虽然荣耀
but he has no power.
却无实权
There's growing unrest in West Chu.
西楚正闹得欢
His Majesty certainly wants stability in North Liang.
陛下自然希望北椋安稳
But he's nursing a viper in his bosom.
可这是养虎为患呢
What about Gu Jiantang?
顾剑棠呢
Didn't he say anything?
他没有说话
He took a sickie.
顾剑棠也称病不出
Is he going to stay in the capital
难道顾剑棠打算一辈子
for the rest of his life?
就留在京城吗
I guess
陛下
His Majesty will make him Grand Commander.
应该会把上柱国给他
doesn't want Gu Jiantang to leave the capital
不愿意放顾剑棠出京城
in case of calamity for the future.
也是怕鱼入深海
Will we just watch the Xu Family
那我们就眼睁睁地看着徐家
rule North Liang from generation to generation?
世世代代统领北椋吗
His Majesty approved of the Hereditament,
陛下给了世袭罔替
but it doesn't mean
不代表徐凤年
Xu Fengnian can live until he takes over North Liang.
就能活到那一天
Among Four Longhu Arch-Taoists,
龙虎四大天师
only you can stay in the capital
唯有你赵丹坪
all year round.
常年留在京城
Over the years,
这些年
you've written
斋醮青词
a lot of sacrificial articles.
写了不少
Aren't you fed up?
还没写腻吗
There's no future for Mount Longhu
朝廷安稳
unless the court is in peace.
龙虎山才有前景
If Xu Fengnian takes over North Liang,
徐凤年接任北椋
it won't be a good thing
对天下
for the world
对龙虎
or Mount Longhu.
都不是好事
You want me to go back to Mount Longhu
你要我回龙虎山
and kill Xu Fengnian?
杀徐凤年
There are four Longhu Arch-Taoists.
龙虎山四天师
Zhao Xituan.
赵希抟
He's your brother's master.
你弟的师父
He'll show some respect to you, I guess.
应该对你能留几分情面
Zhao Danping is the worst-tempered.
脾气最糟的赵丹坪
He resides in the capital,
常年在京城
known as Scholar of Sacrificial Article.
被称为青词学士
He hasn't been back to Mount Longhu for years.
这么多年没回龙虎山
You don't need to worry about him, either.
应该也不用担心他
You should pay attention
所以你要留意的呢
to Zhao Xiyi who has the highest seniority.
也就是辈分最高的赵希翼
Also,
还有
pay attention to Zhao Danxia,
如今天师府掌门
Chief of Arch-Taoists' Office
道门领袖第一人
and the most powerful leader of Taoism.
赵丹霞
They two are horrible enough.
就这两个已经够可怕了
Xu Fengnian
徐凤年
is Xu Xiao's son.
是北椋世子
If we really kill him,
真杀了他
Xu Xiao will lead his army to Mount Longhu!
徐骁就敢马踏龙虎山
You don't need to kill him personally.
你可以不用亲自动手
But he must die.
但他必须得死
This concerns
这件事
the destiny of Liyang.
关系到离阳朝未来的国运
Now that
你们龙虎山
you reap benefits from the court,
既然承受了朝堂的好处
you should
那就该
perform your duty loyally.
为国尽忠
By the way,
对了
besides Xu Fengnian,
除了徐凤年
you should kill one more person.
还有一人要杀
Who?
还有谁
Zhao Kai.
赵楷
Who's he?
他又是什么人
He's Han Diaosi's disciple
韩貂寺的弟子
and the illegitimate son of His Majesty.
陛下的私生皇子
Now,
眼下
he's hunting down Xu Fengnian.
正一路追杀徐凤年
The illegitimate son of His Majesty?
私生皇子
Han Diaosi
韩貂寺
pretends to cooperate with me.
表面与我合作
Actually, he wants to kill Xu Fengnian
其实是想杀掉徐凤年
and cause chaos in the world
引起天下大乱
so that Zhao Kai can fight for the throne.
然后借机让赵楷争夺皇位
He thinks
他自己
I'm ignorant of his plan.
以为能瞒得过我
I've been doing everything
我张巨鹿所做的这一切
for the eternal peace
都是为离阳朝
of Liyang.
万世太平
Xu Fengnian is the bane.
徐凤年是祸根
He must be killed.
不得不杀
Zhao Kai
赵楷
will also cause chaos.
一样是乱因
You can kill him, too.
正好一并除掉
Prime Minister,
宰辅大人
he's an illegitimate son.
虽说是私生的
But he's a prince, anyway.
可他终究是皇子
When you want to assassinate a prince,
暗中杀皇子
have you thought about
您有没有考虑过
how you may end up?
自己的下场
I fight for the destiny of Liyang,
为国运而争
and I can't care about
岂能在乎
my own destiny.
自身的命数
If Han Diaosi
如果韩貂寺
knows about this,
他真的知道了此事
he won't let you go.
他可不会放过你啊
He's a mere eunuch,
一个太监
but he wants to cause big chaos.
还想着引发大乱
He won't let me go.
他不放过我
I won't let him go, either.
我也没打算放过他
But...
不过
Say no more.
行了
I'll handle the problems in court.
朝堂风波我来挡
You shall take care of problems
江湖的事情
in the martial world.
要看你们
Zhao Danping.
赵丹坪
Whose side
你们龙虎山
will your sect be on?
到底选择站在哪边呢
Prime Minister,
宰辅大人
I'm going back to Mount Longhu immediately.
我这就回龙虎山
Xu Fengnian and Zhao Kai
徐凤年和赵楷的命
will be killed
由我龙虎山
by us.
取之